<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>TUYỂN SINH 10 Archives - hướng dẫn</title>
	<atom:link href="https://huongdan.online/category/tuyen-sinh-10/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://huongdan.online/category/tuyen-sinh-10/</link>
	<description>.online</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 15:27:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>vi</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/cropped-logo-web-32x32.png</url>
	<title>TUYỂN SINH 10 Archives - hướng dẫn</title>
	<link>https://huongdan.online/category/tuyen-sinh-10/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF hơn 10 năm qua có đáp án  2023</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-lop-10-mon-anh-tphcm-pdf-co-dap-an-2023/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 06:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tuyển tập đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng anh tphcm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bạn đang tìm kiếm một file Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh TPHCM PDF qua các năm, hoặc bạn đang muốn làm thử các đề thi này để ôn luyện cho kỳ thi sắp tới? Hãy yên tâm, ở trang web của chúng tôi, bạn có thể tải xuống đề thi&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-lop-10-mon-anh-tphcm-pdf-co-dap-an-2023/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF hơn 10 năm qua có đáp án  2023</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-lop-10-mon-anh-tphcm-pdf-co-dap-an-2023/">Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF hơn 10 năm qua có đáp án  2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Bạn đang tìm kiếm một<strong> file Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh TPHCM PDF</strong> qua các năm, hoặc bạn đang muốn <strong>làm thử các đề thi này</strong> để ôn luyện cho kỳ thi sắp tới? Hãy yên tâm, ở trang web của chúng tôi, bạn có thể tải xuống <strong>đề thi được gõ lại sắc nét</strong>, hoặc bạn cũng có thể làm bài trực tiếp và chấm điểm ngay.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" width="1024" height="576" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner-1024x576.png" alt="banner" class="wp-image-341" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner-1024x576.png 1024w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner-300x169.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner-768x432.png 768w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner-600x338.png 600w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/site-banner.png 1120w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cấu trúc đề thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tại TPHCM qua các năm</h2>



<p>Năm 2022, lần đầu tiên số câu hỏi trong đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh tại TPHCM đã bị thay đổi từ 36 câu như mọi khi lên 40 câu. Bên cạnh đó, cấu trúc đề thi và dạng câu hỏi cũng có vài thay đổi. Hãy cùng chúng tôi nhìn lại đề thi qua các năm để phân tích rõ hơn nhé:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2021/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Có thể thấy rõ rằng, đề thi tuyển sinh 10 môn tiếng Anh tại TPHCM từ năm 2018 cho đến năm 2020 vẫn giữ ổn định cấu trúc đề (gồm 36 câu). Nhưng kể từ thời điểm <a href="https://vnexpress.net/tp-hcm-khong-to-chuc-thi-vao-lop-10-4335007.html">kỳ thi tuyển sinh 10 bị hủy vào năm 2021</a> thì đến năm 2022, đề thi tuyển sinh 10 đã xuất hiện thêm 4 câu hỏi nữa, tổng cộng là 40 câu.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Ma trận đề thi năm 2022 bị thay đổi</h3>



<p>Cụ thể, đề thi năm 2022 đã thêm 4 câu hỏi về kiến thức trọng âm và phát âm. Đây là dạng kiến thức chưa từng xuất hiện trong đề thi của tỉnh này suốt hơn 10 năm qua:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2016/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2016</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2015/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2015</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2014/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2014</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2013/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2013</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Việc thay đổi cấu trúc đề vẫn chưa dừng lại ở đó. Nếu chịu để ý, bạn sẽ nhận thấy rằng đề thi năm 2022 có số lượng câu hỏi giao tiếp là 6 câu (câu 7, 8, 9, 11, 13, 14) thay vì 2 câu như trong đề các năm trước. Thực chất trong 6 câu hỏi này không phải toàn hỏi về kiến thức giao tiếng trong tiếng Anh mà còn hỏi về cả giới từ và những kiến thức ngữ pháp khác.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Cấu trúc đề thi bị thay đổi liên tục vào năm 2016 và 2017</h3>



<p>TP.HCM cũng đã từng thay đổi cấu trúc đề thi vào lớp 10 kể từ sau năm 2017. Trước đó, phần hai của đề thi sẽ kiểm tra về nội dung tìm lỗi sai. Nhưng kể từ năm 2018 cho đến nay, dạng câu hỏi này đã bị thay thế hoàn toàn bằng dạng câu hỏi nhìn hình ảnh các biển báo để suy nghĩa.</p>



<p>Trước đó, đề thi năm 2016 cũng đã bị thay đổi cấu trúc so với năm 2015. Cụ thể phần đọc hiểu True, False đã có thêm 2 câu hỏi trắc nghiệm về ý nghĩa của bài đọc và lần đầu tiên dạng bài sắp xếp trật tự câu đã xuất hiện. Ngoài ra dạng câu hỏi biến đổi từ vựng (Verb form, Word form) cũng đã được giảm số lượng 4 câu và gộp chung vào một phần.</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2012/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2012</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2011/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2011</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2010/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2010</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-nam-2009-tphcm/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2009</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Tuy nhiên, cấu trúc đề thi kể từ năm 2015 trở về trước hầu như không bị thay đổi. Duy chỉ có năm 2012, ở phần đọc hiểu, đề thi không cho đoạn văn mà thay vào đó sử dụng hình ảnh của hai tờ rơi quảng cáo để suy luận:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="330" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1024x330.png" alt="đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn anh năm 2012 có hai hình ảnh tờ rơi quảng cáo ở phần bài đọc" class="wp-image-86" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1024x330.png 1024w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-600x193.png 600w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-300x97.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-768x247.png 768w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1536x495.png 1536w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.png 1820w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Còn theo bạn, bạn nghĩ cấu trúc đề thi năm nay sẽ thay đổi ra sao? Hãy để lại bình luận của bạn ở bên dưới.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Download Tuyển tập đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF từ năm 2009 đến nay</h2>



<p>Sau đây là file<strong> Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF</strong> do huongdan.online biên soạn. Ngoài ra, bạn cũng nên làm thử các đề này trực tiếp trên trang web của chúng tôi. Bạn sẽ được chấm điểm tự động với đáp án chuẩn xác nhất. Xin mời bạn đọc tham khảo (file tải xuống nằm ở cuối trang). </p>



<iframe loading = "lazy" src="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1WkiI9WSJUVR_pYLTgTsusmCGZUanpKbn/preview" width="100%" height="600px" style="border:0;"></iframe>



<p>Hy vọng thông qua bài viết hữu ích này sẽ giúp các bạn có thêm nguồn tài liệu bổ ích để chuẩn bị cho kỳ thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 năm 2023 sắp tới nhé.</p>



<p>Tải xuống <a href="https://drive.google.com/u/0/uc?id=1WkiI9WSJUVR_pYLTgTsusmCGZUanpKbn&amp;export=download">File PDF (có đáp án)</a></p>



<p>Link tải xuống File <a href="https://huongdan.online/product/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-tphcm-mon-tieng-anh/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PDF (không đáp án)</a></p>



<p>Link tải xuống <a href="https://huongdan.online/product/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-tphcm-mon-tieng-anh/" rel="nofollow">File Word dành cho giáo viên</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/tuyen-tap-de-thi-tuyen-sinh-lop-10-mon-anh-tphcm-pdf-co-dap-an-2023/">Tuyển tập de thi tuyển sinh lớp 10 môn Anh tphcm PDF hơn 10 năm qua có đáp án  2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH VÀO LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2022 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I.&#160;Choose the word / phrase / sentence (A, B, C or D) that best fits the&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH VÀO LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2022 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi : ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I.&nbsp;Choose the word / phrase / sentence (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence or best answers the question. (3.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. Which word has the underlined part pronounced differently from that of the others?</p>



<p>A. n<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">a</span></strong>tional B. n<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>a</strong></span>tural C. c<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>a</strong></span>rry D. pl<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>a</strong></span>ne</p>



<p>2. Which word has the underlined part pronounced differently from that of the others?</p>



<p>A. innovat<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">ed</span></strong>&nbsp;B. mend<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ed</strong></span>&nbsp;C. receiv<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ed</strong></span>&nbsp;D. celebrat<span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>ed</strong></span></p>



<p>3. Which word has a different stress pattern from that of the others?</p>



<p>A. destruction B. mechanic C. interview D. environment</p>



<p>4. Which word has a different stress pattern from that of the others?</p>



<p>A. littering B. measure C. rubbish D. prevent</p>



<p>5. &#8220;Let&#8217;s congratulate Nam ____ his excellent academic achievement,&#8221; said the teacher.</p>



<p>A. to B. of C. on D. in</p>



<p>6. Our school celebrated ___ Children&#8217;s Day</p>



<p>A. on B. in C. at D. to</p>



<p>7. &#8211; Nam: &#8220;Have you ever enjoyed Tet, Maryam?&#8221;<br>&#8211; Maryam: &#8220;You mean the Lunar New Year? I once had a chance to be in Vietnam then, ____ I really liked it.&#8221;</p>



<p>A. or B. and C. so D. although</p>



<p>8. &#8211; Bao: &#8220;Did you follow SEA GAMES 31,________ held in Vietnam from May 12th to 23<sup>rd</sup>, 2022?&#8221;<br>&#8211; Minh: &#8220;Of course. Viet Nam won over 200 gold medals.&#8221;</p>



<p>A. who is B. which was C. that is D. when was</p>



<p>9.- Mark: &#8220;Viewers from the rural areas can get access to cable television, can&#8217;t they?&#8221;<br> -An: &#8220;Yes, there is _______ local and international programs on different TV channels.&#8221;</p>



<p>A. lots of B. plenty of C. a variety of D. a number of</p>



<p>10. Our teacher suggests ______ waste paper for the school&#8217;s recycling scheme.</p>



<p>A. collecting B. to collect C. being collected D. to be collecting</p>



<p>11. &#8211; Daisy: &#8220;what is your favorite place to ________?<br>&#8211; Lucy: &#8220;Lemongrass Restaurant.&#8221;</p>



<p>A. run out  B. eat out  C. carry out  D. fill out</p>



<p>12. Famers use animal dung to____ their fields.</p>



<p>A. make  B. fertilize  C. run  D. develop</p>



<p>13. – Thanh: &#8220;Why don’t you reduce the amount of water your family uses?&#8221;<br>&#8211; Nga: &#8220;______________&#8221;</p>



<p>A. Nice idea B. Yes, please C. No, Thanks. D. You’re welcome!</p>



<p>14. – Chinh: &#8220;Congratulations! You scored a superb goal for our team.&#8221;<br>&#8211; Tung: &#8220;_________&#8221;</p>



<p>A. Everybody does the same<br>B. It was the whole team’s effort. Thanks!<br>C. Yes, let’s. The crowd was fantastic.<br>D. Thank you. Everybody can solve this problem.</p>



<p><strong>II. Look at the signs. Choose the best answer (A, B, C, D) for questions 15 and 16. (0.5pt)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-8.png" alt="" class="wp-image-202" width="177" height="137"/></figure>



<p>15. What does the sign tell you to do?</p>



<p>A. Pay attention when being on fire here.<br>B. Extinguish fire inside.<br>C. Don&#8217;t play with fire here.<br>D. Exit in the event of a fire.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized is-style-rounded"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-10.png" alt="" class="wp-image-204" width="168" height="161"/></figure>



<p>16. What does the sign mean?</p>



<p>A. Bad students will be punished at school.<br>B. Violence is not allowed at school.<br>C. Classmates should not talk too much to each other.<br>D. Younger students mustn&#8217;t obey their monitors at school.</p>



<p><strong>III. Read the following passage. Decide if the statements from 17 20 are True or False, and choose the correct answers (A, B, C or D) for questions 21 and 22. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>Where did your water come from before it arrived in your kitchen? Is your glass of water as new as this morning or as old as the dinosaurs? Is it even older than the dinosaurs? Water on Earth is always moving round and round, like a wheel turning. This is called &#8220;the water cycle,&#8221; and it has no beginning or end. But to talk about it, we must choose a place to begin. We will start with the oceans, the largest bodies of water on Earth.</p>



<p>In this part of the cycle, the sun heats the water in the oceans, and then the warm water evaporates into the air. The water in the air eventually comes together to form very large clouds. Wind then moves the clouds over the land: When clouds finally meet cold air, the water comes down in the form of rain or snow.</p>



<p>Some of this rainwater will stay on the land, but most of the water goes down into rivers and streams.</p>



<p>Finally, it goes back to the oceans, where the cycle begins again.</p>



<p>The water cycle is billions of years old. So, think again about how old that water in your cup is! It&#8217;s much, much older than you thought.</p>



<p>17. The oceans are the largest bodies of water on Earth……………</p>



<p>18. The water cycle is compared to a wheel turning……………</p>



<p>19. When you look at clouds, you are seeing the beginning part of the water cycle……………</p>



<p>20. Water is made new every day……………</p>



<p>21. Which of the following may be the best title for the reading passage?</p>



<p>A. The beginning of the water <br>B. Water on Earth <br>C. The water cycle <br>D. The age of water</p>



<p>22. In the reading passage, all of the following are mentioned EXCEPT _______</p>



<p>A. The sun makes water hot. <br>B. Water beautifies human life. <br>C. Water is used in the kitchen. <br>D. Clouds and cold air create rain.</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>My sister Susan and I were in the yard (23) _____ with our neighbors&#8217; dog last Saturday afternoon when suddenly the sky turned dark gray. Minutes later, it began to rain heavily, so we ran quickly into the house.</p>



<p>Mom asked us to close all the windows, Just as I shut the window in the kitchen, we heard a loud clap of thunder. Dad took us to the (24) _______ and asked us to keep calm. From there, we could hear the strong wind outside. All of (25)______my sister was startled by a loud crashing noise and started to cry. We tried to calm her down but she was very scared.</p>



<p>After a few minutes, the wind stopped and everything was quiet. We slowly made our way up from the basement. The house was full of glass (26) ______ the broken windows. The real damage was outside though. There were trees on the streets and there were damaged cars all over. Our neighbors were very (27) _________ because they couldn&#8217;t find their dog. We (28) __________ everywhere and finally found him behind some bushes. He got wet all over but luckily was unhurt.</p>



<p>23. A. play B. played C. playing D. to be played</p>



<p>24. A. garage B. basement C. attic D. kitchen</p>



<p>25. A. a sudden B. suddenly C. an immediate D. immediately</p>



<p>26. A. on B. up C. to D. from</p>



<p>27. A. tired B. satisfied C. horrible D. worried</p>



<p>28. A. searched B. phoned C. cried D. watched</p>



<p><strong>V. Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>29. Her father learned that the house was for sale through an ……………(advertise)</p>



<p>30. Physical exercise is …………… to our health. (benefit)</p>



<p>31. In the speaking examination, answers are presented …………… on tape. (oral)</p>



<p>32. She&#8217;s just had an article …………… in the Tuoi Tre. (publish)</p>



<p>33. Tsunami is a natural …………… that can cause great damage. (disastrous)</p>



<p>34. I like watching the news on TV every day because it&#8217;s very …………… (inform)</p>



<p><strong>VI.&nbsp;Rearrange the groups of words in a correct order to make complete sentences. (0.5 pt)</strong></p>



<p>35. Most students tried / Entrance exam / to concentrate / for the coming / on studying /. //</p>



<p>36. Global warming / that happens / over many, many years / is a slow change / . //</p>



<p>35. Most students tried ………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>36. Global warming …………………………………………………………………</p>



<p><strong>VII. Finish each of the following sentences in such a way that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it. (1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>37. How long have you been learning English?</p>



<p>→ When did ………………………………………………………</p>



<p>38. The students spent ten minutes waiting for their bus.</p>



<p>→ It took  ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>39. My uncle will send for a mechanic to fix his car tomorrow.</p>



<p>→ My uncle will have his ………………………………………</p>



<p>40. &#8220;What about teaching the children how to cope with an emergency?&#8221; said Mrs Thu.</p>



<p>→ Mrs Thu suggested that the children ……………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 09:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nếu như bạn đang cần tìm và sưu tầm đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh thành phố Hồ Chí Minh năm 2021. Hãy đọc bài viết này để tìm hiểu thêm nhé. Kỳ thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 TPHCM năm 2021 Vào năm 2021, theo như dự kiến, kì thi&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2021/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2021/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Nếu như bạn đang cần tìm và sưu tầm đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh thành phố Hồ Chí Minh năm 2021. Hãy đọc bài viết này để tìm hiểu thêm nhé.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-12.png" alt="" class="wp-image-250" width="410" height="410" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-12.png 512w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-12-300x300.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-12-100x100.png 100w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-12-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 410px) 100vw, 410px" /></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Kỳ thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 TPHCM năm 2021</h2>



<p>Vào năm 2021, theo như dự kiến, kì thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 tại TP.HCM sẽ được<strong> tổ chức vào ngày 2/6 và 3/6</strong>. Tuy nhiên, vào thời điểm này, tình hình dịch Covid-19 đang diễn biến phức tạp. Cụ thể, TP.HCM đã phải họp khẩn quyết định <strong>giãn cách toàn thành phố</strong> từ ngày 31/5. </p>



<p>Điều này khiến cho TP.HCM phải <strong>lùi kì thi dự kiến sang ngày 22/6 &#8211; 23/6</strong>. Được biết trước đó, có kì thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 của <a href="https://ptnk.edu.vn/">trường Phổ thông Năng khiếu TP.HCM</a> đã được tổ chức thành công từ 26/5 &#8211; 30/5 (trước thời điểm ban quyết định giãn cách).</p>



<p>Thế nhưng sau đó, tình hình dịch bệnh đã không ổn định, TP.HCM đã quyết định dời lịch thi lớp 10 năm 2021 cho đến khi có thông báo mới. Đây là năm đầu tiên và cũng là năm duy nhất (tính đến thời điểm hiện tại) một kì thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 ở TPHCM bị lùi lịch hơn 1 tháng so với dự kiến. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Huỷ thi tuyển sinh. Xét tuyển vào lớp 10 TPHCM năm 2021</h2>



<p>Ngày 3/8/2021, tức sau 2 tháng hoãn kì thi, TP.HCM đã <strong>chính thức huỷ kỳ thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10</strong> công lập năm 2021-2022, thay vào đó quyết định tổ chức <strong>xét tuyển</strong> vào lớp 10 công lập.</p>



<p>Theo đó, điểm xét tuyển sẽ dựa trên điểm trung bình ba môn của học sinh đã đạt được trong năm học lớp 9. Cụ thể đối với thí sinh xét tuyển vào lớp 10 thường (tức không thi chuyên), điểm xét tuyển bằng tổng điểm ba môn: Toán, Văn, Anh cộng lại. Nếu thí sinh dự thi chuyên, điểm xét tuyển sẽ được tính tương tự nhưng được cộng thêm điểm của môn chuyên nhân với hệ số 2.</p>



<p>Sau khi nghe công bố rằng kì thi bị huỷ bỏ, nhiều phụ huynh bức xúc cho rằng việc xét tuyển sẽ không đánh giá đúng năng lực của con họ. Một số học sinh cho rằng quá bất công vì có trường chấm điểm dễ, có trường chấm điểm khó để khuyến khích học sinh học tập. Nhiều phụ huynh đã &#8216;cầu cứu&#8217; vì con rớt cả 3 nguyện vọng trường THPT công lập</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="nv-iframe-embed"><iframe title="Phụ huynh TP.HCM &#039;cầu cứu&#039; vì con rớt cả 3 nguyện vọng 10 trường công lập" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H--2sQefOB4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>



<p>Cũng chính vì vậy, điểm chuẩn xét tuyển vào lớp 10 có xu hướng cao hơn so với hình thức thi tuyển. Sau 20 ngày từ lúc huỷ bỏ kì thi, vào ngày 23/8, <a href="https://vnexpress.net/tp-hcm-cong-bo-diem-chuan-lop-10-4342791.html">TP HCM đã công bố điểm chuẩn lớp 10</a>. Có thể thấy, điểm chuẩn thấp nhất là 15 điểm (thuộc về hai trường THPT ở huyện Cần Giờ), nghĩa là trung bình mỗi môn đạt khoảng 5 điểm. So với <a href="https://tuoitre.vn/da-co-diem-chuan-vao-lop-10-nam-hoc-2022-2023-o-tp-hcm-2022071015051018.htm#content-4">điểm chuẩn thấp nhất của hình thức thi tuyển vào lớp 10 năm 2022</a> là 10.5 điểm, thì chỉ cần mỗi môn được 3.5 điểm là có thể đỗ.</p>



<p>Như vậy, <strong>năm 2021 ở TPHCM không có kì thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 nào được diễn ra</strong>. Thay vào đó, học sinh sẽ được xét tuyển dựa trên tổng điểm học bạ năm lớp 9 của ba môn Toán, Văn, Anh, cộng với điểm ưu tiên (nếu có).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</h2>



<p>Năm 2021, TPHCM không tổ chức thi tuyển sinh 10. Nếu như bạn đang tìm kiếm đề thi tuyển sinh 10 môn tiếng Anh tại TPHCM qua các năm, bạn có thể tham khảo và làm thử trực tiếp các đề thi sau:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2022/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2022</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</a></li>



<li><a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Một điều đang chú ý là, sau khi bị hoãn thi tuyển sinh 10 (năm 2021), cấu trúc đề thi môn tiếng Anh từ năm 2022 đã bị thay đổi so với những năm trước đó. Cụ thể, số câu hỏi đã được tăng từ 36 câu lên 40 câu. Bốn câu hỏi được tăng thêm này kiểm tra nội dung phần phát âm và trọng âm, là các dạng mà chưa từng xuất hiện trong các đề thi trước đây.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2021/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TP HCM năm 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 08:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH VÀO LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 16 tháng 07 năm 2020 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I. Choose the word/phrase A, B, C, or D that best fits the space in each&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH VÀO LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 16 tháng 07 năm 2020 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi : ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I. Choose the word/phrase A, B, C, or D that best fits the space in each sentence. (2.5pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. The government is trying to __________ people to use public buses instead of motorbike.</p>



<p>A. complain B. provide C. reduce&nbsp; D. persuade</p>



<p>2. Watching TV all day is a bad habit __________ we get no physical exercise.</p>



<p>A. but B. even though C. because D. so</p>



<p>3. Valentine’s Day is celebrated __________ February 14th.</p>



<p>A. for B.&nbsp; to C. on D. at</p>



<p>4. We are looking forward to our __________ in the competition.</p>



<p>A. participation B. likeness C. failure D. variety</p>



<p>5. Mr. Tan, who teaches physics here, speaks very __________ English.</p>



<p>A. best B. good C. well D. better</p>



<p>6. The&nbsp;mosque, which Lan walks __________ on her way to school, looks beautiful.</p>



<p>A. past B. into C. through D. across</p>



<p>7. Are you __________ learning on Saturday mornings this term?</p>



<p>A. interested B. likely C. busy D. expected</p>



<p>8.That’s Maryam the girl __________ visited Lan and Nga last week.</p>



<p>A. who B. whom C. whose D. which</p>



<p>9. – Student A: &#8220;Give my best regards to your parents.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;– Student B: &#8221; __________ &#8220;</p>



<p>A. It’s nice of you to say so. B. You’re welcome! C.&nbsp; I’m glad to hear that. D. Thanks. I will.</p>



<p>10. – Student A: &#8220;Would you please wait a while?&#8221;<br>– Student B:&nbsp; &#8221; __________ &#8220;</p>



<p>A. Never mind. B. Certainly! I’ll be right here. C. Of course. I wouldn’t. D.&nbsp; Not at all.</p>



<p><strong>II. Look at the signs. Choose the best answer (A, B, C, or D) for questions 11 and 12. (0.5pt)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized is-style-rounded"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-7.png" alt="no text while driving" class="wp-image-192" width="167" height="167" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-7.png 584w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-7-300x300.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-7-100x100.png 100w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-7-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 167px) 100vw, 167px" /></figure>



<p>11. What does the sign say?</p>



<p>A. not to start the engine with a cellphone<br>B. not to stop and buy a cellphone on the way<br>C. not to use cellphones when driving<br>D. not to talk with friends when driving</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5-1024x239.png" alt="gate B1 arrivals on your right" class="wp-image-190" width="344" height="80" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5-1024x239.png 1024w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5-600x140.png 600w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5-300x70.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5-768x179.png 768w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-5.png 1104w" sizes="(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px" /></figure>



<p>12. What does the sign say?</p>



<p>A. The area where passengers to check in to board<br>B. The area where passengers wait for the flight<br>C. The area where passengers will leave<br>D. The area where passengers from landing come out</p>



<p><strong>III. Read the following passage. Decide if the statements from 13 to 16 are True or False, and choose the correct answer (A, B, C, or D) for questions 17, 18. (1.5pts)</strong></p>



<p>In Britain there is a holiday now which people call Mother’s Day.&nbsp; In the old days many girls from working-class families in towns and cities and from farmers’ families in the country worked in rich houses.</p>



<p>Once a year, it was usually on Sunday in March, they were allowed to visit their mothers. They went home and brought presents for their mothers and for other members of their families. People call that day Mothering Day or Mothering Sunday. Mothering Day later became Mother’s Day. It is the last Sunday in March.</p>



<p>In 1914, President Woodrow Wilson and Congress agreed that the second Sunday in May should be observed as Mother’s Day in America. On that day, children give their mothers flowers, presents and cards to show their love to their mothers. Americans spend millions of dollars to buy Mother’s Day gifts. Clothes, perfume, jewelry and books or tickets to theater are given to mothers. People who cannot be with their mothers on that day usually send them presents and call them all the phone.</p>



<p>13. Mother’s Day is a day on which children show their love to their male parents………………</p>



<p>14. In the United States, Mother’s Day has been celebrated on the second Sunday in May since the early 19th century………………</p>



<p>15. Americans usually offer gifts to their mothers on Mother’s Day………………</p>



<p>16. People who cannot visit their mothers on Mother’s Day often phone to talk to them………</p>



<p>17. According to the passage, Mother’s Day is __________ in Britain</p>



<p>A. the last Sunday in May<br>B. the second Sunday in May <br>C. the last Sunday in March<br>D. the first Sunday in March</p>



<p>18. What does the passage mainly discuss?</p>



<p>A. A day children give someone they respect flowers presents and cards.<br>B. A day when servants could return home to visit their mothers<br>C. A day children show their love to their mothers and fathers<br>D. A day to honor mothers and motherhood</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word/phrase (A, B, C, or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1.5pts)</strong></p>



<p>The changes that took place in schools have changed the roles of teachers. In the past teachers (19) ________ the major source of knowledge, the leader and educator of their students’ school life.</p>



<p>Nowadays teachers provide information and show their students (20) ________ to handle it. Although they are still considered to be a kind of facilitator in the class, they can be thought of as a facilitator in the learning process.</p>



<p>Another difference between the past and present tasks of teachers is represented by the (21) ________ background they need in order to be able to use computers and some other machines effectively. Instead of teaching with chalk, they need to be information technology experts.</p>



<p>One of the biggest challenges (22) ________ teachers is that their role in the school management has also changed. The school needs them as individuals who can make (23) ________ and cope win the stress of the world of schools. At the same time, teachers need to be able to work in teams, and cooperate with colleagues and parents. A teacher has not only to instruct but also to (24) ______ the students with confidence and determination.</p>



<p>19. A. used to be &nbsp; B. were used to be&nbsp;C. got used to being &nbsp; D. were being used</p>



<p>20. A. who B. how &nbsp; C. what D. which</p>



<p>21. A. media B. cultural &nbsp; C. technical D. social</p>



<p>22. A. in B. by &nbsp;C. on D. for</p>



<p>23. A. decisions B. experiences &nbsp; C. difficulties D. mistakes</p>



<p>24. A. design B. prevent &nbsp; C. inspire D. inform</p>



<p><strong>V. Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>25. ………., my childhood friends get together for entertainment. (occasion)</p>



<p>26. Her performance was so …………… that we all stood up to clap our hands. (impress)</p>



<p>27. The …………… for the Best Actress cried when her name was announced. (nominate)</p>



<p>28. Most accidents can be avoided if people pay more ……………… (attend)</p>



<p>29. The aim is to raise people’s awareness of the …………… of rhinos.&nbsp; &nbsp; (conserve)</p>



<p>30. My creative sister spends most of her free time …………… her own room. (decorate)</p>



<p><strong>VI. Rearrange the group of words in a correct order to make complete sentences. (0.5pt)</strong></p>



<p>31. / have been added / fashionable / Modern patterns/ to make it more / to the Ao dai /. /</p>



<p>32. / language is / Nowadays, / compulsory for / students of all ages / learning a foreign /. /</p>



<p>Thí sinh viết tiếp các nhóm từ và dấu câu theo đúng trình tự vào Phần trả lời để hình thành câu hoàn chỉnh:</p>



<p>31. Modern patterns ………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>32. Nowadays…………………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p><strong>VI. Rewrite each of the following sentences to another way so that it means almost the same as the sentences printed before it. (2pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. “Why don’t you clear up the garbage before leaving, Linh?” said Mai.</p>



<p>Mai suggested that……………………………………………</p>



<p>34. We haven’t used these machines for a long time.</p>



<p>It’s been……………………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. Thu is the best tennis player in the club.</p>



<p>No one else in the club can…………………………………</p>



<p>36. It’s a pity they are travelling on uncomfortable buses.</p>



<p>They wish they…………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2020/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 16:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KỲ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2019 tại TP.HCM&#160; Môn thi: ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I.&#160;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&#160;(2.5 pts)&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KỲ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2019 tại TP.HCM&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi: ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I.&nbsp;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&nbsp;(2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. My uncle, _______ is a computer programmer, works at New York’s Columbia University.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. whom&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. whose&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. who&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. which</p>



<p>2. The whole incident was captured ___________ CCTV at the shopping mall yesterday.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. at&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. on&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. in&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. above</p>



<p>3. Internet users often suffer various risks, such as spam or ___________ junk mail.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. scientific&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. electric&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. electronic&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. traffic</p>



<p>4. In 2019 Brunei has a __________ of just over 439,300.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. currency&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. collection&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. religion&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. population</p>



<p>5. Last weekend, Ba invited Liz to join his family on a&nbsp; ____________ to his home village.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. two-days trip&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. two-day trip&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. trip of two-day&nbsp;&nbsp; D. two-day’s trip</p>



<p>6. The __________ lot is kept under video surveillance, so you needn’t worry about your car.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. parker&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. parking&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. parks&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. park-keeper</p>



<p>7. The Internet is available almost everywhere now ________, some people have never got access to it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. Although&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. So that&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. However&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. Therefore</p>



<p>8. Most robots are empowered by artificial ______, or AI, and machine learning technology</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. intelligence&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. internet&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. information&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. interest</p>



<p>9. &#8211; Hai Dang: &nbsp;&#8221; Do you think wearing uniforms is a good idea?&#8221;<br>&#8211; Minh Dan: “_____”</p>



<p>A. Well done. You did it<br>B. Yeah. You don’t have to think of what to wear every day<br>C. It’s nice of you to say so <br>D. Yes, I can. And so can all of my friends.</p>



<p>10. -Tim: “___________________”<br>-Paul: “I disagree. The course is too expensive for us”</p>



<p>A. That academy isn’t good&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. That summer course is unaffordable&nbsp;<br>C. Do you like that course?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. Why not take that summer course?</p>



<p><strong>II. Look that the signs.&nbsp;Choose the best answer (A, B, C or D) for each sign (0.5 pts)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized is-style-rounded"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-4.png" alt="image for sign A" class="wp-image-170" width="216" height="216" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-4.png 438w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-4-300x300.png 300w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-4-100x100.png 100w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-4-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 216px) 100vw, 216px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">(A)</figcaption></figure>



<p>11. What does the sign (A) say?</p>



<p>A. You mustn&#8217;t drive after drinking.<br>B. You shouldn&#8217;t drive under the influence of drugs.<br>C. You must be careful with drunk drivers.<br>D. You should be careful as there is a pub ahead.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-3.png" alt="image of sign B" class="wp-image-169" width="207" height="222" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-3.png 326w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-3-279x300.png 279w" sizes="(max-width: 207px) 100vw, 207px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">(B)</figcaption></figure>



<p>12. What does the sign (B) say?</p>



<p>A. Disabled people can stand here.<br>B. This is a forbidden area for the handicapped.<br>C. Facilities for disabled people are available here.<br>D. The handicapped must stay here at all times.</p>



<p><strong>III.<em>&nbsp;Read the following passage. Decide if the statements from 13 to 16 are True or False and choose the correct answer (A, B, C or D) for the questions 17 and 18.</em></strong></p>



<p>There is a list of interesting jobs that we&#8217;ll never have again, and a town crier is, of course, on the list. it&#8217;s been a long time since town criers worked professionally, so there are not many people knowing who town criers were. Today we can only see them in the movies or at some old tourist sites. Before newspapers were invented, a town crier, who was usually an older gentleman with a booming voice, always dressed officially and had a little bell which he carried with him always. His job was to go through city streets ringing the bell and shouting the latest news as he was walking.</p>



<p>The occupation of the town crier was quickly replaced by radio, television, texting, internet, and all the marvels of modern technology. Today this occupation exists only for entertaining purposes and as local folklore. Competitions for the best town criers are still being held in some parts of the world like America. Australia, Canada and England.</p>



<p>13. A lot of people now work as professional town criers.…………</p>



<p>14. Today people can get to know about town criers in films and at some tourist attractions.…………</p>



<p>15. Town criers had worked professionally before mass media were invented.…………</p>



<p>16. Town criers used to wear casual clothes when working.…………</p>



<p>17. What is the passage mainly about?</p>



<p>A. The birth of town crying<br>B. Town crying, an extinct job<br>C. Town criers and modern technology<br>D. Town crying for entertainment</p>



<p>18. It can be inferred from the passage that town criers used to</p>



<p>A. live in a town square.<br>B. be waited and welcomed to town squares. <br>C. make loud deep sounds.<br>D. take part in competitions in western countries</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1,5pts)&nbsp; &nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>There are many ways to cut the (19)_____ of your power bill in your home.&nbsp; Take a look at the way we choose computers (a laptop or a desktop computer). A laptop is a computer that is small enough (20)_______ carried around easily and is flat when closed. While a desktop computer is the one that fits on a desk but that is not easily moved from place to place.</p>



<p>Regardless of their convenience difference, choosing a laptop or a desktop computer may result in a significant difference in energy (21)______ . I’m writing this by using a laptop with power (22)________ features switched on – using around 50 watts maximum. Back some years ago, I would work with a desktop computer with a 17’’ CRT screen – around 300 watt all told.</p>



<p>The following are some rough (23)_________ based on coal fired power generation for just the computer aspect:</p>



<ul>
<li>Laptop = 50w x 10 hours a day x 365 days = 185.5 kilowatt hours</li>



<li>Desktop = 300w x 10 hours a day x 365 = 1095 kilowatt hours</li>
</ul>



<p>In the case of coal fired electricity, each kilowatt you save not only puts (24)______ back into your pockets, but also avoids up to 1.5 pounds of carbon dioxide emission being generated.</p>



<p>19<strong>. </strong>A<strong>.</strong>&nbsp;energy&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. costs&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;C. households&nbsp;&nbsp;D. power</p>



<p>20.&nbsp;A. having&nbsp; B. being&nbsp;&nbsp;C. to be&nbsp;&nbsp;D. to have</p>



<p>21.&nbsp;A. efficiency&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;B. affection&nbsp;&nbsp;C. production&nbsp;&nbsp;D. effect</p>



<p>22. A. consuming&nbsp;&nbsp;B. lighting&nbsp;&nbsp;C. saving&nbsp;D. sleeping</p>



<p>23. A. innovations&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;B. productions&nbsp;&nbsp;C. settings&nbsp;&nbsp;D. calculations</p>



<p>24.  A. cash&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;B. debt&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. product&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;D. economy</p>



<p><strong>V.&nbsp;Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence.&nbsp;(1.0pt)</strong></p>



<p>25. Ha Noi will have&nbsp;…………&nbsp;between 23°C and 27°C.&nbsp;<strong>[temperate]</strong></p>



<p>26. It&#8217;s worrying that natural disasters are becoming&nbsp;…………&nbsp;damaging.&nbsp;<strong>[increase]</strong></p>



<p>27. UFO stands for ………… Flying Object&#8221;, which is also known as a flying saucer.&nbsp;<strong>[identify]</strong></p>



<p>28. Although robots have proved to be significant, they still have a few&nbsp;………….&nbsp;<strong>[limit]</strong></p>



<p>29. You can finish the work at home on Sunday if&nbsp;………….<strong>&nbsp;[necessity]</strong></p>



<p>30. The police&nbsp;…………. to the emergency quickly and the victims were rescued.&nbsp;<strong>[response]</strong></p>



<p><strong>VI.&nbsp;Rearrange the groups of words in a correct order to make complete sentences (0.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>31. India, downing trees / and power lines, causing /has hit / widespread damage/ A powerful cyclone /./</p>



<p>32. what would you do?/ If you had / and playing games endlessly, a 15-year-old/boy staying up too late/./</p>



<p><strong>Thí sinh viết tiếp nhóm từ và dấu câu theo đúng trình tự vào phần trả lời để hình thành câu hoàn chỉnh.</strong></p>



<p>31. A powerful cyclone ………………………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>32. If you had ………………………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p><strong>VII.&nbsp;Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it (2.0pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. Nowadays young people pay more attention to traditional festivals than they did some years ago.</p>



<p>→ Some years back&nbsp;young …………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>34. This is the first time they have experienced the wonderful feeling in space.</p>



<p>→ They have never ………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. We should teach young children to care for the environment.</p>



<p>→ I suggest young children&nbsp;…………………………………………</p>



<p>36. Drivers and passengers must fasten the seat belt when travelling in cars.</p>



<p>→ It is compulsory for&nbsp;……………………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-10-mon-anh-thanh-pho-ho-chi-minh-nam-2019/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào 10 môn Anh TPHCM năm 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 15:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2018 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-group is-layout-constrained wp-block-group-is-layout-constrained"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2018 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi : ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian phát đề)</strong></p>
</div></div>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence. (2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. Are you ______ teaching on Saturday mornings this term?</p>



<p>A. enjoy&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. likely&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. busy&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. expected</p>



<p>2. I hope _______ to know this beautiful city better.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. to have&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. to get&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. to need&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. to appear</p>



<p>3. Jeff completely ignored what I said and _____ on eating.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. put&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. tried&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. went&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. depended</p>



<p>4. The ones about _________ I have been worried these days are the students of mine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. that&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. whom&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. whose&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. which</p>



<p>5. I suggest that we should ______ people from catching fish by using electricity.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. let&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. relate&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. prohibit&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. encourage</p>



<p>6. Mr. Loc, who teaches Math here, speaks very ______ English.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. best&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. good&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. well&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. fluently</p>



<p>7. Watching TV all day is a bad habit _____ we get no exercise and eat unhealthy snacks.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. but&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. though&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. because&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. therefore</p>



<p>8. A recycled plastic bottle saves enough ______ to run a 60-watt light bulb for 6 hours.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. energy&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. money&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. electron&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. life</p>



<p>9. -Hai Anh: “_______”<br>-Minh Phuong: “Why not?”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. You should cook the meal now&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. How about cooking the meal now?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Have you cooked the meal?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. We’d better be cooking the meal.</p>



<p>10. -Sue: “Thank you very much for your donation.”<br>-Peter: “______”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. Yes, do it now&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. Sure, I’ll do it&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Not a chance&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. It’s my pleasure</p>



<p><strong>II. Look at the signs. Choose the best answer (A,B,C or D) for each sign&nbsp;&nbsp; (0,5 pt)</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="260" height="190" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.png" alt="In the picture: there is a car on a rocky road" class="wp-image-161"/></figure>



<p>11. What does the sign say?</p>



<p>A. You can drive as fast as you can.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. Beware of careless drivers&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Slippery road is ahead&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. You cannot drive a care on this road.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="210" height="208" src="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-2.png" alt="In the picture: there is one person throwing garbage to the bin" class="wp-image-162" srcset="https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-2.png 210w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-2-100x100.png 100w, https://huongdan.online/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-2-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" /></figure>



<p>12. What does the sign say?</p>



<p>A. Littering is permitted here<br>B. We must not use recycle bins.<br>C. We must put waste paper into the bin<br>D. Dust bins can be found everywhere.</p>



<p><strong>III. Read the following passage. Decide if the statements from 13 to 16 are True or False and choose the correct answer (A, B, C or D) for the questions 17 and 18. (1.5pt)</strong><br>We can develop alternative sources of energy, and unless we try we’ll never succeed. Instead of burning fossil fuels we should be concentrating on more economical uses of electricity, because electricity can be produced from any sources of energy. If we didn’t waste so much energy, our resources would last longer. We can save more energy by conservation than we can produce for the same money. Unless we do research on solar energy, wind power, tidal power, hydroelectric plants … our fossil fuels will run out and we’ll all freeze or starve to death. Several countries are spending much more time and money on research because the energy from the sun, the waves, and the winds last forever. We won’t really survive unless we start working on cleaner and safer sources of energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>13. Fossil fuels are renewable sources of energy.………</p>



<p>14. Electricity can be produced from the sea.………</p>



<p>15. The energy from the sun, the waves and the winds will never be used up.………</p>



<p>16. We really need to worry about cleaner and safer sources of energy.………</p>



<p>17. What is the passage mainly about?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. We are facing huge lack of energy.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. Electricity is the main energy we use.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Alternative sources of energy must be developed.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. It is impossible to have safer sources of energy.</p>



<p>18. Which source of energy cannot last forever?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. coal&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. wind &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. water&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. waves</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1.5 pts)</strong><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two British policemen were (19)_______ to investigate a flying saucer on March 31, 1989, the day before April Fool’s Day. When the policemen arrived at a field in Survey, they saw a small figure wearing a silver space (20)________ walking out of a spacecraft. Immediately the police ran off in the opposite direction. Reports revealed that the alien was in fact a small person, and the flying saucer was a hot air balloon that had been specially built to look (21)________ a UFO by Richard Branson, the 36-year-old chairman of Virgin Records.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Branson had planned to (22) _______ the balloon in London’s Hyde Park on April 1. However, a wind change had brought him down in a Survey field. The police received a lot of phone calls from terrified motorists as the balloon drifted over the motorway. One lady was so (23)_____ by the incident that she was crying as she was (24)______ the UFO to a radio station.</p>



<p>19. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A.run&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. sent&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. spent&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. come</p>



<p>20.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. suit&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. cloth&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. denim&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. linen</p>



<p>21.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. like&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. as&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. for&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. after</p>



<p>22. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. fly&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. land&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. erupt&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. collapse</p>



<p>23. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. pleasing&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. terrific&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. shocked&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. amazed</p>



<p>24. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. telling&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. saying&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. phoning&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. describing</p>



<p><strong>V. Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence. (1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>25. Have you read the …………… of our school closing ceremony?&nbsp;&nbsp;(announce)&nbsp;</p>



<p>26. In the 18th century jean cloth was made …………… from cotton.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(complete)</p>



<p>27. The next stage in the development of television is …………… TV.&nbsp;&nbsp; (active)</p>



<p>28. Some …………… have raised people’s awareness of rhinos’ protection.&nbsp;&nbsp;(conservation)</p>



<p>29. Sweden has a(n) …………… solar energy program.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(advance)</p>



<p>30. We all enjoy listening to his …………… stories&nbsp;&nbsp;(humor)</p>



<p><strong>VI. Rearrange the groups of words in a correct order to make complete sentences (0.5 pts)</strong><br>31. that family members/ a celebration/ Tet is so important/ try to come back home/ living apart/./</p>



<p>32. and developing nations/ the rivers and seas/ for polluting/ Both developed/ are responsible/./</p>



<p>Thí sinh viết tiếp nhóm từ và dấu câu theo đúng trình tự vào phần trả lời để hình thành câu hoàn chỉnh:</p>



<p>31. Tet is so important ……………………………………………………………………………….</p>



<p>32. Both developed …………………………………………………………………………………….</p>



<p><strong>VII. Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it. (2.0pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. We are eager to make a trip to the countryside this July.</p>



<p>We are looking………………………………………………</p>



<p>34. It’s two months since we last saw a movie.</p>



<p>We haven&#8217;t …………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. Minh does not speak English as well as Lan.</p>



<p>Minh wishes he …………………………………………</p>



<p>36. Stop using the computer after 10 P.M.</p>



<p>You must shut ………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2018/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2018</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 15:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2017 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Khoá ngày 02 tháng 06 năm 2017 tại TP.HCM</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Môn thi : ANH VĂN</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề)</p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence. (2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. Are you very busy _______ Monday mornings? – No! I always have time for a cup of coffee </p>



<p>A.from B.to C.out D.on</p>



<p>2. London is also known _______ “The Square Mile” beacause its area is almost one square mile. </p>



<p>A.with B. of C.as D.for</p>



<p>3. She didn’t hear the dog barking outside beacause she _______ headphones. </p>



<p>A.wore B.was wearing C. wearing D. is wearing</p>



<p>4. That is Maryam, the girl _______ visited Lan and Nga last week. </p>



<p>A. who B. whom C. whose D. which</p>



<p>5. She felt a little bit cold, _______ she put on her coat. </p>



<p>A. or B. because C. so D. but</p>



<p>6. My Japanese pen pal, Yoko, speaks English very ________. </p>



<p>A. best B. excellent C. well D. good</p>



<p>7. I like the new idea of those _______ spoons which can be eaten after use as it is made of good rice. </p>



<p>A. edible B. inedible C. poisonous D. wooden</p>



<p>8. One plastic bottle recycled saves enough energy to run a 60-watt light _______ for 6 hours. </p>



<p>A. bulb B. standard C. electricity D. bill</p>



<p>9. David :”It’s terrible. I don’t think I will be able to pass the exam.”<br>– Mary : “____________________” </p>



<p>A. Let’s try it B. Don’t worry. Everything will be all right. C. Ok. What’s that? D. Why not pass it?</p>



<p>10. Sue : “You have read that article on the website, haven’t you”<br>– Peter : “_____________” </p>



<p>A. Sure, thanks B. Not at all! Go ahead. C. Not yet. Why? D. Yes, of course, I will.</p>



<p><strong>II. Choose the underlined word or phrase (A, B, C or D) that needs correcting. (0,5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>11. (A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">Don’t</span> use so much fossil fuel (B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">although</span> there (C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">will be</span> nothing (D) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">left</span> for future generations.</p>



<p>12. Recycling plastics (A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">reduce</span> the (B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">amount</span> of oil (C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">needed</span> for (D) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">making</span> new plastics.</p>



<p><strong>III. Read the following letter. Decide if the statements from 13 to 16 are True or False and choose the correct answer (A, B, C or D) for the questions 17 and 18. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>Today almost everyone walking down the street has at least one mobile phone in their pocket. That is because many mobile phones are upgraded every year around the world, and most people are interested in changing their old mobile phone for a new one. There has been an estimated number of 90 million unwanted mobile phones in the UK alone! This mountain weighs around 12,000 tonnes, but only about 5% of it is recycled. What makes us worried most is that mobile phones contain harmful chemicals which are released into the environment when phones begin to degrade and, in addition, large amounts of carbon dioxide are also produced during the manufacture of phones. It seems that the more modern mobile phones become, the worse our environment gets.</p>



<p>13. Mobile phones are modernized every year around the world.…………</p>



<p>14. Most people are keen on having a newer mobile phone.…………</p>



<p>15. About half of unwanted mobile phones in the UK are recycled.…………</p>



<p>16. Old mobile phones do no harm to the environment .…………</p>



<p>17. What is the passage mainly about? </p>



<p>A. The modernization of mobile phones is necessary.<br>B. There are more and more mobile phones in the world.<br>C. The modernization of mobile phones make the environment worse.<br>D. The manufacture of phones produces carbon dioxide.</p>



<p>18. Which of the following can be inferred from the passage? </p>



<p>A. Modern mobile phones are worse for the environment than the older ones.<br>B. Mobile phones are getting cheaper and more modern.<br>C. People in the UK are very concerned to recycle old mobile phones.<br>D. Used mobile phones can pollute the environment.</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1,5pts)</strong></p>



<p>In many Western countries, people (19)_______ Halloween on October 31st. The word Halloween (20)________ from “All Hallows’ Eve”. It is the night before All Saints’ Day, a religious holiday in some parts of the world. On this night, children dress up in special costumes, put (21)________ masks, and go door to door saying “trick-or-treat” to get candy. Many people decorate their homes with paper ghosts, black cats or witches to give their houses a (22) _______ look. People also decorate their homes with jack-o-lanterns. They carve scary faces on pumpkins, and (23)_____ candles inside the pumpkins. In some places, both children and adults can make (24)______ of haunted houses. They all seem very excited about the festival.</p>



<p>19. A. celebrate B. reduce C. save D. exchange</p>



<p>20. A. gets B. goes C. comes D. reaches</p>



<p>21. A. in B. off C. out D. on</p>



<p>22. A. bored B. relaxed C. careful D. scary</p>



<p>23. A. light B. to light C. lighting D. lighted</p>



<p>24. A. parts B. tours C. turns D. prizes</p>



<p><strong>VI. Use the correct tense or form of the verb given in each sentences. (1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>25. My pen pal was really ………… by the beauty of Ha Long Bay. (impress)</p>



<p>26. Both competitors are ………… strong and fast. (surprise)</p>



<p>27. The company has made a new motorbike having very low fuel ………….. (consume)</p>



<p>28. A large number of car accidents are caused by fast and ………… driving. (care)</p>



<p>29. Could you send me details of courses for …………, who have never learnt English before. (begin)</p>



<p>30. Ba’s family and Liz had a very ………… day in the countryside last weekend. (enjoy)</p>



<p><strong>VI. Rearrange the groups of words in a correct order to make complete sentences (0.5pt)</strong></p>



<p>31. have lost their lives / Many people around the world / natural disasters / and homes because of / . /</p>



<p>32. The survival of / depends on each and / the natural world / every one of us /./</p>



<p>Thí sinh viết tiếp nhóm từ và dấu câu theo đúng trình tự vào phần trả lời để hình thành câu hoàn chỉnh.</p>



<p>31. Many people around the world ……………………………………………………………………</p>



<p>32. The survival of ………………………………………………………………………………</p>



<p><strong>VII. Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it, (2.0pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. He can’t drive because he’s very young</p>



<p>He is not …………………………………………</p>



<p>34. City life is not as peaceful as country life.</p>



<p>Country life is ………………………………………</p>



<p>35. It’s not safe for kids to go hunting Pokémon on the street.</p>



<p>Going hunting ………………………………………</p>



<p>36. The boy hasn’t visited his grandparents for two months.</p>



<p>The boy last ………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2017/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2017</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2016</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2016/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 10:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2016 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I.&#160;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&#160;(2.5&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2016/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2016</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2016/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2016 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi : ANH VĂN</strong> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I.&nbsp;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&nbsp;(2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. Disneyland __________ its 60<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;birthday on Saturday 18 July, 2015.</p>



<p>A. celebrated&nbsp;B. congratulated&nbsp;&nbsp;C. complicated&nbsp;D. complimented</p>



<p>2. __________ the 3<sup>rd</sup>&nbsp;day of the Lunar New Year, pupils often pay their teachers a visit.</p>



<p>A. To&nbsp; B. On&nbsp; C. In&nbsp;&nbsp;D. At&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>3. Our little son was sleepy when we were walking to the park;________, we went home early.</p>



<p>A. therefore&nbsp; B. however C. moreover D. although</p>



<p>4. People _________ do not love nature may not love anything else in life.</p>



<p>A. whom&nbsp;&nbsp;B. whose&nbsp;&nbsp;C. which&nbsp;&nbsp;D. who</p>



<p>5. Speaker 1: “Excuse me. Do you mind if I sit here?”<br>– Speaker 2:”_________”</p>



<p>A. You’re right&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. Not at all! Go ahead&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Sure, thanks.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. Really? Good!</p>



<p>6. The small bamboo forest _________ the entrance to the village makes it picturesque.</p>



<p>A. at&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. in&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. on&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. to</p>



<p>7. About 70% of the earth’s __________ is covered with water.</p>



<p>A. world&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. atmosphere&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. ocean&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. surface</p>



<p>8. The teacher ________ Van if she had ever tried calling a helpline.</p>



<p>A. said&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. advised&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. asked&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. suggested</p>



<p>9. Speaker 1: “______”<br>Speaker2 : “Sơn Đoòng is a new tourist destination.”</p>



<p>A. Let’s eat out this evening!<br>B. We need a holiday, dear!<br>C. I miss my relatives in Huế!<br>D. I’d like to cook something special food.</p>



<p>10. I chose to buy the house in District 9 ______ avoid noise and pollution.</p>



<p>A. so that&nbsp; B. in order that C. so as to D. in order not</p>



<p><strong>II.&nbsp;Choose the underlined word or phrase (A, B, C or D) that needs correcting. (0,5 pt)</strong></p>



<p>11. One of the great&nbsp;(A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">pleasures</span>&nbsp;of&nbsp;(B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">to travel</span>&nbsp;to another country (C)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">is</span>&nbsp;eating (D)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">different</span>&nbsp;dishes.</p>



<p>12.&nbsp;(A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">The drought</span>&nbsp;(B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">that caused</span>&nbsp;by El Nino (C)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">weather patterns</span> (D)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">is hitting</span>&nbsp;Thailand and Cambodia.</p>



<p><strong>III.&nbsp;Read the following letter. Decide if the statements from 13 to 16 are, True or False and choose the correct answer (A, B, C or D) for the questions 17 and 18. (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>Dear Daddy,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am writing this to tell you how much you are missed and loved, especially on such a special day as today. I will always remember that day – my graduation day. You were standing there with tears in your eyes while I was walking towards the stage to get my diploma, a moment in time that would last forever. You are such a devoted father who has always taken very good care of family and me. I now live independently, Dad, and I’ve experienced the difficulties of being and adult, and I am going to have my own children with all the burden of being a parent. I understand and love you more. After all, I will always be your little naughty son! Happy Father’s Day.</p>



<p>13. This is a letter written by a man to his father.……………</p>



<p>14. The father cried when his son was on his way to the stage.……………</p>



<p>15. The letter is sent from a son to his father on the son’s graduation day.……………</p>



<p>16. The writer of this letter has no difficulty living an adult’s life.……………</p>



<p>17. What is the letter mainly about?</p>



<p>A. The writer’s study at university<br>B. The writer’s childhood memory<br>C. The writer’s thankfulness to the father<br>D. The writer’s marriage life.</p>



<p>18. Which of the following can be inferred from the letter?</p>



<p>A. The father is quite irresponsible<br>B. The writer is in disagreement with the father<br>C. The writer has a lot of experience in work.<br>D. The writer very much respects the father.</p>



<p><strong>IV. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage<em>. (1,5pts)</em></strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Britain will soon ban smoking in cars with children. Britain’s government wants (19)______ the harm cigarette smoke does to children. New laws will cut the chances of children passive smoking. This is when someone breathers in the&nbsp; (20)______ from other people’s cigarettes. Many studies say passive smoking can almost be as (21) ______ as actually smoking a cigarette. The British government says that it has looked at research pointing out that children who sit in smoke-filled cars have (22)_____ problems. It in particularly bad in cars because there is so little space, so the car fills with smoke very quickly. (23)_________ agrees with the new law. Some lawmakers argue that it takes away the freedom for people to smoke in their own car. However, Britain’s health minister states that the health of children is more (24)___________ than the freedom to smoke.</p>



<p>19. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;A. reduce&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. to reducing&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. to reduce&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. reducing</p>



<p>20. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. gas&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. tobacco&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. smell&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. smoke</p>



<p>21.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. harmful&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. heavy&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. careless&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. tired&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>22.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. traffic&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. housing&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. health&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. economic</p>



<p>23.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. Everyone&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. No one&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. Not everyone&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. Every lawmaker</p>



<p>24. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A. important&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. useful&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. serious&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. interesting</p>



<p><strong>VI.&nbsp;Use the correct tense or form of the verb given in each sentences.&nbsp;(1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>25. The local government has plans to …………… this city.(modern)</p>



<p>26. That exchange student can speak English and Spanish …………….&nbsp;(fluent)</p>



<p>27. Nowadays, Vietnamese women still wear ao dai, especially on a special …………….&nbsp;(occasional)</p>



<p>28. Some styles of jeans in the 1960s were …………… jeans, painted jeans and so on. (embroider)</p>



<p>29. Too much …………… on the parent spoils a child. (depend)</p>



<p>30. Despite the benefits of the Internet, the users sometimes suffer …………… risks.&nbsp;(variety)</p>



<p><strong>VI.&nbsp;Rearrange the groups of words in a correct order to make complete sentences (0.5pt)</strong></p>



<p>31. considerable progress/ our parents were/ all of us had made/ happy to hear/./</p>



<p>32. and friendly environment/ to practice your English/ offers you a good/ the Academy of Language/./</p>



<p><strong>Thí sinh viết tiếp nhóm từ và dấu câu theo đúng trình tự vào phần trả lời để hình thành câu hoàn chỉnh.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Answers:</strong></p>



<p>31. Our parents were&nbsp; ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>32. The Academy of Language&nbsp;……………………………………………………</p>



<p><strong>VII.&nbsp;Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it (2.0pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. What a pity! We cannot try all the special food of the village.</p>



<p>→ We wish we……………………………………………………</p>



<p>34. “I want to send my son to a university in the UK”, she said</p>



<p>→ She said that……………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. You will pass this entrance examination with enough hard work.</p>



<p>→ If you don’t work……………………………………………………</p>



<p>36. The Prime Minister will open three more new schools in the town next autumn.</p>



<p>→ Three more new schools will……………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2016/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2015</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 09:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2015 tại TP.HCM Môn thi: ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I.&#160;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&#160;(2.5 pts)&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2015/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2015</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2015/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2015 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi: ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p><strong>I.&nbsp;Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&nbsp;(2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>1. West Malaysia and East Malaysia ________ comprise an area of 329,758 sq km.</p>



<p>A. each other&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. together&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. one another&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. both</p>



<p>2. We have arranged to meet each other ________ 8:00 AM this weekend.</p>



<p>A.to &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;B. on&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. in&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. at</p>



<p>3. Juventus did their best;_______ , Barcelona won the match and the cup.</p>



<p>A. but &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; B. however&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. moreover&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. otherwise</p>



<p>4. The examiner ______ that they keep silent during the exam.</p>



<p>A. said&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. requested&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. told&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. admired</p>



<p>5. &#8211; “ I promise I will study harder next term.” <br>– “_________”</p>



<p>A. Good idea&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. I hope so&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. No, thanks&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. I’m sorry I can’t</p>



<p>6. People speak Malay, English, Chinese and Tamil _____ Malaysia</p>



<p>A.at &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. in&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. on &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;D. to</p>



<p>7. You should reduce _________ of water your family uses.</p>



<p>A. the number&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. the quality&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. a number &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;D. the amount</p>



<p>8. A lot of Vietnamese people who live _________ want to celebrate Tet in Viet Nam, their motherland.</p>



<p>A. foreign &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. far&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. &nbsp;aboard&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. abroad</p>



<p>9. Peter, bring a raincoat just _________. It looks like rain to me.</p>



<p>A. in case&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. in time&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. in turn&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. in spite</p>



<p>10. Typhoons often ___________ in Viet Nam from June to November.</p>



<p>A. predict&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; B. occur&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; C. pass&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. warn</p>



<p><strong>II.&nbsp;Choose the underlined word or phrase (A, B, C or D) that needs correcting.&nbsp;(0,5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>11. (A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">She asked</span>&nbsp;me (B)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">if I am able&nbsp;to</span> speak&nbsp;(C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">any other foreign language</span>&nbsp;and I said (D)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">that I could speak Thai</span>.</p>



<p>12. AAG&nbsp;(A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">has confirmed</span>&nbsp;the (B)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">broken in some</span>&nbsp;of the&nbsp;(C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">sections</span> of&nbsp;the (D)&nbsp;<span style="text-decoration: underline;">undersea cable</span>.</p>



<p><strong>III.&nbsp;Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1,5pts)</strong></p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The word <em>jeans</em>&nbsp;(13) ______ from a kind of material that was made in Europe. It is a strong material and it does not (14)_______ out easily. In the 1960s, many university and college (15)_____ wore jeans. Designers made different styles of jeans to match the 1960s’ fashions; embroidered jeans, painted jeans and so on. In the 1970s more and more people started wearing jeans because they became (16)_______. In the 1980s jeans finally became (17) _____ fashion clothing when famous designers started (18)______ their own styles of jeans, with their own labels on them. Sales of jeans always go up and up because jeans have never been out of fashion.</p>



<p>13. &nbsp;A. gets &nbsp; B. goes &nbsp; &nbsp;C. arrives&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; D. comes</p>



<p>14. A. go  B. wear C. call D. come</p>



<p>15. A. teenagers B. pupils C. students D. youngsters</p>



<p>16. A. higher B. costlier C. longer D. cheaper</p>



<p>17. A. low B. high C. up D. old</p>



<p>18. A. doing B. getting C. making D. buying</p>



<p><strong>IV.&nbsp;Read the passage, then decide if the statements that follow it are True or False.&nbsp;&nbsp;(1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>Are you looking for a cheap, clean, effective source of power that doesn’t cause pollution or waste natural resources? Look no further than solar energy from our sun. Many countries are already using solar energy. Solar panels are placed on the roof of a house and the sun’s energy is used to heat water. The energy can be stored for a number of days, so on cloudy days you can use solar energy too. Sweden has an advanced solar energy program. There, all buildings will be heated by solar energy; cars and buses will use solar power instead of gas by the year 2015.&nbsp;</p>



<p>19. Few countries in the world are ready to use solar energy.………</p>



<p>20. We can hardly use solar energy on cloudy days.………</p>



<p>21. Solar panels are used for water heating.………</p>



<p>22. Some types of vehicles in Sweden will use solar power by 2015.………</p>



<p><strong>V.&nbsp;Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence .&nbsp;(1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>23. We are worried that rivers and canals are becoming more and more ……………&nbsp;<strong>(pollute)</strong></p>



<p>24. TV …………… are advertisements in which goods and services are promoted.&nbsp;<strong>(commerce)</strong></p>



<p>25. It is …………… that some people poach fish in the Nhieu Loc Canal. <strong>(disappoint)</strong></p>



<p>26. Christmas is …………… celebrated in many countries.&nbsp;<strong>(joy)</strong></p>



<p>27. Here is tomorrow’s weather …………… Ho Chi Minh city will be sunny, and…<strong>(cast)</strong></p>



<p>28. My sister is wearing a T-shirt of the latest model. She always dresses …………….&nbsp;<strong>(fashion)</strong></p>



<p><strong>VI.&nbsp;Use the correct tense or form of the verb given in each sentences.&nbsp;(1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>29. Unless she …………… the flowers regularly, they will wither.&nbsp;<strong>(water)</strong></p>



<p>30. We all expect that Anh Vien …………… the most outstanding athlete in this SEA GAMES.<strong>&nbsp;(become)</strong></p>



<p>31. He …………… five comic books since last Monday.&nbsp;<strong>(read)</strong></p>



<p>32. The teacher suggested …………… these units carefully.&nbsp;<strong>(revise)</strong></p>



<p><strong>VII. Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it. (2.0 pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. Emily is sick today, so she cannot go to school.</p>



<p>→&nbsp;If Emily ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>34. We consider Messi a soccer genius. He plays for Barcelona, Spain.</p>



<p>→ Messi, who we ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. People celebrate Passover in Israel in late March or early April.</p>



<p>→ Passover ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>36. The last time we saw the film was 10 years ago</p>



<p>→ It has ……………………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2015/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM năm 2015</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM Năm 2014</title>
		<link>https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2014/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[huongdan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 02:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[TIẾNG ANH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TUYỂN SINH 10]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ĐỀ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TPHCM]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://huongdan.online/?p=109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNGKhoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2014 tại TP.HCM Môn thi : ANH VĂN Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề) Bắt đầu làm bài I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence.&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2014/" class="" rel="bookmark">Đọc tiếp &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM Năm 2014</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2014/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM Năm 2014</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>KÌ THI TUYỂN SINH LỚP 10 TRUNG HỌC PHỔ THÔNG<br>Khoá ngày 11 tháng 06 năm 2014 tại TP.HCM</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Môn thi : ANH VĂN</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Thời gian: 60 phút (không tính thời gian giao đề)</strong></p>



<button id = "doTest">Bắt đầu làm bài</button>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>I. Choose the word/ phrase (A, B, C or D) that best fits the space in each sentence. (2.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">1. &#8211; “Do you like watching the news. Thang?” <br> – “ ________. It’s very informative.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A. Yes, I do B. Not really C. No, I don’t D. Quite the opposite</p>



<p>2. Plastic bags seem good for carrying things. _________, people carelessly throw them away after use.</p>



<p>A. Because B. However C. Although D. Therefore</p>



<p>3. An anthem is a song which is sung _____ special occasions.</p>



<p>A. of B. at C. on D. in</p>



<p>4. It was the world’s _________volcanic eruption in more than 50 years.</p>



<p>A. large B. larger C. the largest D. largest</p>



<p>5. The 2014 UN Day of Vesak attracted thousands of Buddhists from nearly 100 countries _____ the world.</p>



<p>A. on B. at C. around D. above</p>



<p>6. In the afternoon, when Tam ________ his homework, he helps Mr. Brown on the farm.</p>



<p>A. takes B. completes C. does D. makes.</p>



<p>7. Mr. Bao said , “I am so _______ of having been a Dien Bien Phu soldier.”</p>



<p>A. interested B. excited C. proud D. keen</p>



<p>8. They ______ go fishing offshore if they had a bigger boat.</p>



<p>A. can B. may C. could D. will</p>



<p>9. “To the __________________ me to love this country.”</p>



<p>A. person teaches B. man that teach C. one who teaches D. who teaching</p>



<p>10. – “______________”<br> – “But Grandma, the forecast says it’ll be sunny.”</p>



<p>A. Remember the new words by heart<br>B. Let’s eat out<br>C. Let me go shopping<br>D. Don’t forget to bring along a raincoat</p>



<p><strong>II. Choose the underlined word or phrase (A, B, C or D) that needs correcting. (0,5 pt)</strong></p>



<p>11.Plastic is (A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">make</span> from natural gases and (B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">petroleum</span> – a (C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">thick</span> oil that people remove (D) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">from</span> the earth.</p>



<p>12. The festival was (A) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">an</span> opportunity to (B) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">tighten</span> solidarity and (C) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">friendly</span> to make a (D) <span style="text-decoration: underline;">better society</span>.</p>



<p><strong>III. Choose the word (A, B, C or D) that best fits the blank space in the following passage. (1,5pts)<br></strong>If you ask me about the person who has the most influence on my life, I must (13) __________ you it is my father. You ask me what I think about my father. Great! great! My father is the best person in the world. Do you know what I (14) __________? He is a considerate and generous man who is loved not only by his family (15) __________ by all his friends. His great sense of humor (16) __________ him from others. To his colleagues, he is a (17) __________ man who is always helpful and creative in his job. In a word, my father’s terrific! I’m so happy to have him as a friend, an advisor, and (18) __________ a father. I love him so much. Happy Father’s Day, Daddy!</p>



<p>13. A. speak B. say C. tell D. talk</p>



<p>14. A. suppose B. expect C. believe D. mean</p>



<p>15. A. but also B. and also C. but as well D. and neither</p>



<p>16. A. amuses B. takes C. prevents D. distinguishes</p>



<p>17. A. hard-work B. working-hard C. hard-working D. work-hard</p>



<p>18. A. besides B. almost C. above all D. at least</p>



<p><br><strong>IV. Read the passage, then decide if the statements that follow it are True or False. (1.0 pt)<br></strong>The ao dai, the traditional dress of Vietnamese women, has a long history. In the early 17th century, Vietnamese clothing designers made changes to the design of the traditional Chinese costume, creating the primitive forms of the present ao dai. This creativity showed Vietnam’s strong sense of independence. The ao dai, with different designs and materials, was traditionally worn by both men and women. Over the years, despite the coming of western clothing for more convenience in daily activities of modern life, the ao dai has been there to stay. Therefore, Vietnamese women go on wearing this unique dress, which is both traditional and fashionable and which conveys our rich culture to the world.</p>



<p>19. The ao dai had its start at the beginning of the 17th century.……………</p>



<p>20. Vietnamese ao dai and Chinese dresses are exactly the same.……………</p>



<p>21. Both men and women wore the ao dai in Vietnam many years back.……………</p>



<p>22. Although a little inconvenient in modern life, the ao dai is uniquely fashionable.……………</p>



<p><strong>V. Use the correct form of the word given in each sentence . (1.5 pts)</strong></p>



<p>23. The drivers have left lots of garbage on the ground after their …………… (refresh)</p>



<p>24. One of the things that make our country …………… is the East Sea. (beauty)</p>



<p>25. The …………… were disappointed that people had spoiled the area. (environmental)</p>



<p>26. That industrial country is seeking and exploiting …………… resources to satisfy its demand. (nature)</p>



<p>27. To attend the course, you first need to pass our …………… Vietnamese test. (speaking)</p>



<p>28. The fishing boat was …………… damaged in the storm. (bad) </p>



<p><strong>VI. Use the correct tense or form of the verb given in each sentences. (1.0 pt)</strong></p>



<p>29. If the weather …………… bad tomorrow, we will not go camping. (be)</p>



<p>30. You should take part in …………… used paper and cans for recycling. (collect)</p>



<p>31. No one …………… picnic lunches for us yet. (provide)</p>



<p>32. I can also …………… with my friends by means of e-mails. (communicate)</p>



<p><strong>VII. Rewrite each of the following sentences in another way so that it means almost the same as the sentence printed before it. ( 2.0 pts)</strong></p>



<p>33. It’s a pity I don’t have more time for my hobby.</p>



<p> I wish ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>34. Why don’t you make posters on energy saving?</p>



<p> I suggest that you ………………………………………………</p>



<p>35. “We are keen on setting out to sea again,” said the fishermen.</p>



<p> The fishermen said that ……………………………………………………</p>



<p>36. They began using that computer three months ago.</p>



<p> That computer has ………………………………………</p>


<button id = "chamdiem">Chấm điểm (xem đáp án)</button>
<div id = "dapAn"></div>
<script  type = "text/javascript" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/onlincode/hdo@9aebe500d93e9be489b3842bc2d63844e7015f91/ts10anhhcm.js"></script>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/de-thi-tuyen-sinh-vao-lop-10-mon-tieng-anh-tphcm-nam-2014/">Đề thi tuyển sinh vào lớp 10 môn Tiếng Anh TPHCM Năm 2014</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://huongdan.online/">hướng dẫn</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
